Ryan Maguire

21 Glenmore, College Road

Galway, H91KPF1

ryanmaguire48@gmail.com

Objective

Highly motivated Computer Science graduate with one year of industry experience as a Digital Technologist at Medtronic. Pursuing a challenging position in software engineering to leverage my technical skills, problem-solving abilities, and experience in digital transformation.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science and Information Technology, National University of Ireland, Galway

Graduation Date: August 2022

Result: 1:1 Honors (79% Overall)

Relevant Coursework: Database Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Machine Learning, Programming, Systems Modelling, Distributed Systems, Cybersecurity, Algorithms & Data Structures

Skills

- Programming languages: Java, Python, C basic, C#, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Digital Transformation
- Augmented Reality (AR)
- CAD, SOLIDWORKS
- Project Management
- Problem-Solving
- Thin Client Management
- Cross-functional Collaboration & Communication

Work Experience

Digital Technologist | Medtronic Parkmore, Galway | June 2022 - Present

Worked as part of the Smart Digital Factory Program, focusing on Augmented Training, Digital Line Design, and Digital Pitch Dashboards.

Developed augmented training scenarios, resulting in a significant reduction in operator training times, generating savings as a result.

Successfully deployed over 30 Dell thin client devices on the manufacturing floor to display key Digital Pitch Dashboards, resulting in improved operator target tracking and reduced machine downtime.

Spearheaded the use of a Digital Line Design AR tool within the organization through live demos and meetings, upskilled engineers to independently use the tool.

Facilitated collaboration among groups of engineers across three different product lines via the Digital Line Design Tool, equating to reduced design time and cost, reduced environmental impact and improved risk analysis.

Cashier | Ladbrokes Woodquay, Galway | January 2022 - May 2022

Student Internship | Medtronic Parkmore | February 2021 - August 2021

Collaborated with the Smart Digital Factory team to contribute to the development and implementation of innovative solutions in a manufacturing environment.

Engaged in hands-on experiences and learning opportunities within the dynamic field of digital transformation.

General Worker | SPAR Group Ballyconnell | August 2018 - September 2020

Projects

HoloLens 2 Introductory Application | Final Year Project, National University of Ireland, Galway

Led the comprehensive research, development, and management of a Microsoft HoloLens 2 application spanning eight months.

Furthered key skills in Unity development, project management, C# programming, and testing.

Utilized the wide range of AR capabilities available on HoloLens 2 to create engaging user interactions and games that teach the user about the utilities of HoloLens 2.

Implemented thorough user testing and version control using Git & GitHub.

Tempe AR Project | Medtronic Parkmore, Galway, Ireland

Completed an initial pilot for one manufacturing work step, initially saving over \$100,000 US dollars and reducing the training time on average by half.

Development of the solution was completed through the Worklink AR platform, models were generated within SolidWorks, and Media was gathered onsite in Tempe and edited back in Ireland using VSDC.

After a successful pilot, a further seven steps were developed, equating to another \$150,000 US dollars in savings.

Volunteer Experience

Science & Technology Festival 2023 | University of Galway, Galway Ireland | November 2023

Developed an engaging and interactive Augmented Reality (AR) simulation featuring a blocked artery. Demonstrated the transformative impact of inserting a stent to restore normal blood flow.

This educational initiative aimed to enlighten children on the significance of heart health, educate them about Medtronic's role in medical advancements, and provide hands-on experience with state-of-the-art AR technology.

Movember | Galwegians Rugby Club, Galway Ireland | November 2023

Participated in the Movember charity movement with the local rugby club to raise funds for men's mental health by growing a mustache throughout November.

Languages

English (Fluent), Irish (Intermediate)

References

Available upon request.